One Hand Is Enough
-Hey, did you see that?
-What?
（男子学生１）おい見た？
（男子学生２）何？
Yeah, I saw him. Fudo, right?
（男子学生３）見た見た見た
不動(ふどう)だろ
-Did he have plastic surgery?
-He changed way too much overnight.
（男子学生１）あれ整形？
（男子学生４）一晩で変わりすぎ
（男子学生５）全身別人だって
人格から変わったろ
-His whole body is different.
-Even his personality changed.
He's done a total 180.
（男子学生４）180パー違うし
That's seriously Fudo?
（男子学生１）マジ不動？
（女子学生１）不動のヤツ
クスリでもやったんじゃない？
Fudo probably did drugs or something.
（女子学生２）引くなー それ
That creeps me out.
自分を変えたいタイプだったのかね
I guess he wanted to change.
（女子学生１）
あいつ絶対チェリーだよ
He's so distant it's weird.
He's definitely a virgin.
距離感おかしいもん
まだ開かない？
It still won't open?
（女子学生２）んー 何か
バカになってんのかな
Maybe it just doesn't work anymore.
（女子学生１）
お前 いいケツしてんなー
You have a nice ass.
Here you go. Take this!
おわ！ おらおらおら！
（女子学生２）え ちょ… いやん
（２人の笑い声）
（女子学生２）あ…
（女子学生１）ふっ 不動くん！
Fudo...
（女子学生２）いやっ 今の その…
We were just...
（女子学生１）あっ 鍵が…
Oh, the key.
（不動 明(あきら)）ううああっ！
開いたぜ
（女子学生たち）あああ…
It's open now.
すごーい不動くん
That's amazing, Fudo.
ありがとう！
Thanks.
-Fudo!
-That was so cool!
（女子学生１）
今のかっこよかったー！
-Do you want to have lunch together?
-My image of him changed.
（女子学生２）ねえ！
お昼一緒に食べない？
（女子学生３）
何かイメージ変わったー
I've always wanted to talk to you.
（女子学生４）
一度お話してみたかったの！
（明）はあ…
ガキはお断りだ
I don't do kids.
（女子学生たち）
きゃーっ！ かっこいい！
What's with him?
（男子学生１）何だよ
You guys are way different, too.
（男子学生２）
お前らも変わりすぎだろ
（女子学生１）不動くん
すごい食べっぷり！
Fudo, you can eat so much.
-I'm falling for you.
-Hey, eat mine.
（女子学生２）しびれるー
（女子学生３）ねえ私のも！
-Mine, too.
-Eat mine, too.
（女子学生４）私のも！
（女子学生５）私のも食べて！
Oh, my God!
&lrm;（&lrm;ＡＶ女優）
&lrm;やばい あん ああん
AUDIOVISUAL ROOM
（男子学生１）やばいって
やばいよ やばいってば
-This is bad!
-Hey, hey, hey.
-This is crazy!
-Crap!
-This is bad, Fudo!
-You can hear everything outside!
おい！ やべーよ不動！
（男子学生２）外に丸聞こえじゃん
-He has a huge bulge!
-Fudo! He has a boner.
（女子学生１）きゃー不動くん
（女子学生２）立ってんじゃない
-He's so cool!
-Run!
（女子学生３）走ってー
（女子学生４）速そうー
-He must be good!
-Go, go!
What happened to Fudo?
He's totally different.
（陸上部員１）
何があったんだ 不動のヤツ
別人じゃん
It's not normal for a person
to change that much in a day.
（陸上部員２）１日で変われる基準
超えてますから
（陸上部員１）しっかし
陸上部きっての鈍足だろ
He's the slowest runner
on the team.
見た目変わったからって
能力 そんな急に変わんないよな
His can't be better all of a sudden
just because his looks changed.
Get ready...
（陸上部マネージャー１）よーい
（陸上部員３）えっ
えっ
（ミーコ）ええ？
（女子学生たちの歓声）
（明）すげえ！ 何だこの体
Wow, what is this body?
全く重力を感じない
伸び伸びとしたキック…
My legs are free from gravity.
My arms sail in the wind.
風切る腕…
（一同）ああっ…
（女子学生１）速い
（女子学生２）すごい
Oh, crap.
（明）えっ？ やべっ
Ten seconds.
&lrm;（陸上部マネージャー２）
&lrm;10&lrm;秒！
10秒！？
Ten seconds?
（女子学生１）すごーい
（女子学生２）めっちゃ速かった
That was super fast.
-Wasn't that fast?
-That was amazing!
（女子学生３）速かったんじゃない
（女子学生４）すごーい
（牧村美樹(まきむらみき)）どうしたの明くん！
はあ はあ…
What happened, Akira?
いやー まぐれ
追い風かなー ははっ
It was dumb luck.
-Maybe I had the wind at my back.
-No way.
（美樹）そんなわけない
（女子学生）不動くんタオル！
-Fudo, here's a towel!
-Use mine!
（明への歓声が続く）
はあ はあ
はあ はあ はあ
（美樹）４継一緒にやろうよ
陸甲(りくこう)勝てるかも
Let's do a 4-by-100 relay.
-We might win the Koshien event.
-Sounds good.
いいね～ でも今のは
正真正銘のまぐれだよ
But that was genuinely dumb luck.
（美樹）そんなわけない
It can't be.
きゃーっ
（メールの受信音）
美樹ー！ 長崎(ながさき)さんからメッセ！
Miki, you have a text from Mr. Nagasaki.
（美樹）あは…
（長崎光司(こうじ)）キョウコちゃん
来週の日曜どお？
Kyoko. Are you free next Sunday?
かわいい水着あるからさ
（ノックの音）ん？
I have a cute swimsuit for you.
やあ えっと 美樹ちゃんの…
Hey. You're Miki's...
I'm Kuroda.
（ミーコ）黒田(くろだ)です
美樹ちゃん 忘れ物があって
来ません
Miki left something behind
and won't be coming.
（美樹）昨日はありがとう
助けてくれて
Thanks for rescuing me yesterday.
（明）はっ 俺 何もしてねえ
I didn't do anything.
（美樹）かっこよかった
（明）エヘヘッ
You were cool.
しっかし その体すごいねー
Anyway, what's with that body of yours?
まさかドーピングしたわけじゃ
ないんでしょ？
You're not doping, are you?
（明）まあね
No, I'm not.
でも この体
腹が減ってしょうがねえや
But this body gets so hungry.
ふん ひと事みたいに
自分の体でしょー
You talk like it's someone else's.
It is yours, right?
急に変わったんで びっくりしたよ
Your sudden change surprised me.
Me, too.
（明）俺もそうさ
（美樹）ん？
まだこの体の使い道が分かんねえ
I still don't know how to use this body.
（ビートボックスの音）
（ガビ）
♪うっ クソみてーなこの街
Sick of this fucking town
Turning this wheelbarrow 'round
また今日もリアカーを転がし
未だに見えねー未来
Can't see the future,
No revolution, no effort to give
こない時代
そりゃやる気しない
（ワム）♪おい！ 確かに
この街は掃き溜め
Yo, it's true this town is junk
But I'm not giving up just yet
でも俺は口にしない諦め
All I do is win
All I do is win,
and I won't finish here or now
こんなとこで終わる気はねー
（バボ）♪まぁまぁ 落ち着いて
Well, well
Just calm down, cool down now
cool downしてこう
This fightin' between us
Ain't what we about, guys
身内同士 揉め事なら
どぎついぜ
（ワム）♪uh わりー
正直言いすぎた
Sorry, my bad
I went too far and said too much
だからそう気にすんな
生きるんだこのリバーサイ uh
So, don't give a shit
We're gonna live by this river
（一同）イェ～ うーいっ
Yeah.
（ガビ）誰だよ お前
Who the hell are you?
海から来た人魚だよ
かばん取りに来た
The mermaid from the faraway sea.
I came to get this bag.
（ワム）あ？ 昨日のヤツと違うな
The guy from yesterday? No way.
（ガビ）渡し板
粉々にしたってヤツか？
You mean the guy
that shot up this dock?
（銃声）
関係ねえ
それは白いヤツに言ってくれ
That wasn't me.
Talk to the guy in white.
（ワム）じゃあ
そいつの居場所 教えてくれよ
Tell us where he is.
こっちは被害に遭ってんだ
He's caused damage.
（明）はあ…
んなん てめえらみたいな
クズに―
Hey.
If I say I won't tell you scum anything,
what would you do?
教えねえっつったらどうする？
（ワム）くっ
（ガビ）何っ
What?
片手で十分だ
One hand is enough.
（美樹）明くん！？
Akira?
（明）あ…
クソッ
Shit.
ちきしょうめ
Damn it.
は…
（美樹）あ… わっ
（明）俺の体は悪魔に！ 悪魔に！
My body turned into a devil. A devil!
あ…
HISTORY: MURDER, UNSOLVED, DEMONOLOGY,
SABBATH, DEMONS, GYMS, QUALIFIERS
IMAGES
（牧村太郎(たろう)）
おいっ ターコ 邪魔だよ
Hey, Tako, you're in the way.
もおー
Jeez.
（チャイムの音）
Delivery here!
（業者）お届け物でーす
Akira!
（太郎）明兄ちゃん！ バイク！
届いてるよ！
There's a bike for you!
From someone named Ryo!
了(りょう)って人から！
（バイクのエンジン音）
かっこいいね！
明兄ちゃんが乗るの？
It's so cool!
Are you going to ride it, Akira?
了！
Ryo!
（明）俺は… 俺の体は…
Am I...? Is my body...?
どうなってしまったんだ！
What happened to it?
了！
Ryo!
（明）豪華な部屋だな
病室とは思えねえ
What a luxurious room.
It's not like a hospital at all.
大丈夫か？
How are you?
Happy to see you, Ryo.
よかった 了！
（飛鳥(あすか) 了）奇跡的な回復力らしい
足はもう少しだがな
Apparently, I have amazing resilience.
My legs will heal soon.
お前が生きててくれてよかった
I'm glad you're alive.
あのバイク最高だぜ
That bike is amazing.
（了）お前が使ってくれ
You can use it.
お前を巻き込んで
大変なことになってしまった
I dragged you into this,
and now you're in trouble.
本当に申し訳ない
I'm so sorry.
（明）よせよ
Stop it.
俺は覚えてないんだ
お前を助けようとして―
I don't remember.
I tried to save you and next thing I knew
my body changed into this.
気がついたら この体に…
（了）お前がすぐこの病院に
運び込んでくれたおかげで―
I survived because you brought me
to this hospital right away.
俺は助かった
他のサバトの連中は？
What about the others
at the Sabbath?
（了）お前が悪魔を倒し 助けた
You defeated the devils and saved them.
You don't remember that?
覚えていないのか？
（明）んー…
無意識に俺は この体を使って
皆を助けたってことか…
I unconsciously saved everyone
by using this body.
俺がこの体になったのは
無駄ではなかったってことだな
So, it wasn't a waste
that I turned into this, right?
（了）もちろん
Of course not. You gained the power
to battle devils as equals,
お前は武器や道具がなくとも―
悪魔と対等に戦える力を
手に入れた
even without any weapons or tools.
悪魔にない心を持ったままでだ
But you still have a heart,
which devils don't.
お前は悪魔の体と
人間の心を合わせ持つ男―
You're a man
who has the body of a devil
and the heart of a human.
Devilman.
“デビルマン”だ
デビルマン
Devilman...
俺が今 人間の意思を
保っていられるのは―
The fact that I can sustain a human heart
偶然かもしれない…
might be a coincidence.
もし俺が 悪魔のように
人を傷つけだしたら―
If I start hurting people like a devil,
すぐに殺してくれ
kill me right away.
俺も自分がコントロール
できないと分かれば―
If I start to lose control of myself,
フィキラと同じように死を選ぶ
just like Fikira,
I'll choose death.
ん？
秘書のジェニーだ 大丈夫
She's my secretary, Jenny. It's okay.
エロすぎんじゃねえか
She's way too erotic.
クンクン
（了）お前のためだ
その体を維持するには―
It's for you.
You need a lot of energy
to fuel that body of yours.
相当のエネルギーが必要だろ
いいのか？
Are you sure?
実を言うと
牧村さんちは野菜ばっかで―
Honestly, it's mostly veggies
at Makimura's place,
もの足んなくてな
so, it hasn't been enough.
This body is amazing.
この体はすごい
下手するとバイク以上の
スピードと馬力だ
It might have more speed
and power than the bike.
これからも できるだけ
俺の所で補給するといい
You should refuel  at my place
as much as possible from now on.
お前には その体を使って
やってほしいことがあるんだ
There's something I want you to do
with that body of yours.
（食べる音）
（長崎）夜な夜な 誰もいない
くず鉄置き場から―
You can hear loud music every night
大音量の音楽が流れてきて―
from an empty scrap metal yard,
and you can hear something
like a dying scream sometimes.
時折 人の断末魔のような
叫び声が聞こえてくるんです
（長崎）これもサバトっていう 闇の
パーティーなんじゃないですかね―
This might also be
the dark party called Sabbath.
次は潜入して撮ろうかと
思うんですが
I'd like to sneak in and get a shot.
（編集長）悪魔とかサバトとか
そんなのはいいんだよ
I don't care about things
like devils or Sabbath.
この間の“陸上界の魔女”は
どうしたよ
What about the Track Witch?
Can you take a bikini shot?
水着くらい撮れないのか？
（長崎）うう…
そっちもやってるんですが…
I'm working on that, too, but...
（編集長）お前の本業は若い子の裸
盗み撮りすることだろう
Your job is to photograph naked bodies
of young people.
It's out of your league.
10年早(はえ)えよ
（激しい音楽）
（住職）おわっ ぐあっ
That bastard.
この野郎
俺を なめんなよ！ おい！
Don't... Don't mess with me!
Hey!
く… はあ…
本物の銃だぞ！
It's a real gun!
そこにいるのは分かってるんだ！
撃つぞ！
I know you're there!
I'll shoot!
撃つぞー！
ふっ ふっ ふっ
うわあっ やめろ！
離せ！ 離せ！
Stop! Let me go! Let me go!
は… はな… 離…
Let...
（叫び声）
（体が潰れる音）
（住職）うひっ ああああ！
（カイム）暴力衝動が
抑えられないとは―
They can't even fight
their violent impulses. How foolish!
しかたのないヤツらだ
（シレーヌ）我慢にも限界はある
我々本来の姿だ
There's a limit to patience.
That is our true form.
Let them get it out of their system.
発散くらいさせてやれ
性衝動を抑えるのさえ ひと苦労だ
It's hard just
to fight back sexual urges.
（カイム）
アモンがこちらへ来るまで―
Till Amon comes to us,
私はいくらでも
君を慰める用意があるよ！
I am ready to comfort you
however you need.
美しきシレーヌ！
Beautiful Silene.
カイム！ お前が
このシレーヌの相手にだと？
Kaim. You as the partner? To me?
不釣り合いだ！
You're no match.
（カイム）ふっ
（牧村ノエル）主よ
この食事を祝福してください
Lord, please, bless this meal.
体の糧が心の糧となりますように
May this food nourish our souls.
今日 食べ物に事欠く人にも
必要な助けを与えてください
Please, help those
less fortunate than us.
アーメン
-Amen.
（一同）アーメン
やったあ お肉だあー
We have meat!
（ノエル）明くんはこれくらいじゃ
もの足りないんじゃないか？
Akira,
this isn't enough for you, is it?
明くん
昼間 ごはん すごかったの
Akira ate so much for lunch today.
女の子たちの行列ができて―
There was a huge line of girls,
みんなが“食べてー”って
貢いだ物―
and he ate everything that they gave him.
全部食べちゃって
（ノエル）すごい人気なんだな
You're really popular.
（太郎）じゃあ 明兄ちゃん
もうお肉いらないよね
Then you don't need any more meat,
right, Akira?
そんなハンバーグくらい
ひと飲みで食えちゃうぜ
I can eat a hamburger patty like that
in one gulp.
（太郎）いや！ それダメ！
No, don't!
（一同の笑い声）
（太郎）お兄ちゃんは
おかかごはんでいいでしょー
You should just have dried bonito flakes
with rice.
（牧村亜樹子(あきこ)）宝仙寺(ほうせんじ)の住職さん
まだ帰ってこないって
Apparently, Hosen Temple's chief priest
hasn't come back yet.
こないだお父さんになった
ばかりなのに 心配だな
He just recently had a child.
That's worrying.
He probably got caught by an evil devil.
悪い悪魔につかまったんだよ！
太郎！ 冗談でも
そんなこと言っちゃダメ
Taro, you shouldn't say that,
even as a joke.
悪魔と約束すると
強くなれるんだって！
You can get stronger
if you make a deal with a devil.
そんなのテレビの話でしょ！
That's just a story on TV.
太郎 悪魔は私たちに
甘い言葉をささやくが―
Taro, devils may sweet talk us,
but you shouldn't get taken in by it.
それに乗ってはいけないんだ
いいね
Okay? We have love,
and we are well-educated.
我々には愛や教養がある
The guy at the temple has tons of guns,
（太郎）お寺のおじちゃん
銃いっぱい持ってるんだよ―
He also has tons of watches,
and has them on under his sleeve.
時計もいっぱい持ってて
袖の下にたくさんつけてるんだ
（美樹）ウソ言いなさい
You're lying.
昼間 奥さんと話してたら
突然泣きだしちゃって
I talked to his wife today.
She started crying suddenly.
（太郎）
見せてもらったんだよ！
He showed them to me.
（太郎）
見せてもらったんだよ！
う う…
何でもないといいけどな
I hope nothing happened.
そのうち帰ってくるよ
（美樹）ふ…
He'll be back eventually.
（激しい音楽）
（女のあえぎ息）
（シレーヌ）ああーっ！
（明）はっ！
はあ…
んん…
う…
（牧村ノエル）ほら あそこに
東京タワーが見えるだろ
See? There's Tokyo Tower there, right?
こっちからは富士山が見えるぞ
You can see Mount Fuji from here.
ほら よーく見てごらん
Here. Take a good look.
If the weather is nice,
遠くにあっても
天気がよければ見えるんだ
you can see it,
even if it's far away.
（美樹の鼻歌）
（携帯電話の着信音）
（美樹）ん 牧村です
This is Makimura.
Hey, Miki.
There's something I wanted to show you.
やあ美樹ちゃん
ちょっと見せたい物があってね
どう 見える？
いいスタジオだろ？
Well? Can you see?
Isn't it a great studio?
ちょうど今 ここ空いててね
This place happens to be free.
（明）今日もよく見えるぜ
You can see it today, too.
（長崎）前にも言っただろ？
I've told you before, I don't want
to photo you as an athlete.
アスリートじゃない君を
撮ってみたいって
（美樹）興味ないです
No, thank you.
（長崎）前に撮った写真
すごい反響なんだよ
The previous photo got amazing feedback.
&lrm;ん…
Everyone wants to get to know you, Miki.
みんなが美樹ちゃんのこと
知りたがってさ…
（美樹）わっ
（明）わっ！
（長崎）わっ！
わわっ ああ… ぐっ…
明くん！
Akira!
（長崎）誰だ お前は！
-Who the hell are you?!
-I'm sorry.
すみません！
お母さんの友達の息子さんで
It's my mom's friend's son.
（長崎）ああ 居候の
（美樹）あ
Oh, the freeloader.
What are you doing? That was rude.
何するの 失礼でしょ！
おい！ 早く美樹ちゃんに戻せ！
Hey, give the phone back to Miki!
（電話が切れる音）
あっ
頑張ってる人なのよ！
今はグラビアに甘んじてるけど―
He's working hard.
He photos bikini models,
but getting into journalism.
ゆくゆくは報道にって！
（明）美樹は困ってる
You need help, Miki.
Everyone works hard.
誰も頑張ってる
こいつは美樹の真面目なところに
つけ込んでるんだ！
He's taking advantage of your earnestness.
What's wrong with being earnest?
真面目で何がいけないのよ！
ん…
WORLD TRACK AND FIELD
SPRINTING TECHNIQUE
（ミーコ）あ…
ん…
That's good, Miko.
（長崎）いいよ ミーコちゃん
Very sexy.
セクシーだね
いい胸してるよね
You have nice breasts.
（ミーコ）やめてください！
Please, don't.
あ！
（動物のような声）
DEVILMAN
（デビルマンの主題歌が流れる）
DEVILMAN OPENING
（太郎）おおー
（ターコの鳴き声）
（バイクのエンジン音）
（了）サバトが
悪魔の侵入口なのは分かった
The Sabbath is the entryway
for the devils.
次に人間界に隠れた
悪魔の悪行をあぶりだす
We'll uncover the crimes of devils
hiding in the human realm.
警察が立件できてない殺人が
行われた形跡がある場所を―
Search places with evidence of murder
the police couldn't build a case for.
しらみつぶしに当たる
（明）ずいぶんあるな
Looks like there's a lot of it.
巻き込んですまない
Sorry to drag you into this.
ハハッ 巻き込まれたのは
出会った時からだ！
You dragged me into this when we met.
（長崎）来い 来い 来い 来い
Come on, come on.
んっ
（デーモン１）
また川沿いのヤツらか
The guy from the river again?
（長崎）あっ
（デーモン２）頻繁だと
足がつきやすいんだよ
It's easier to get tracked
if we do it often.
文句ばかり言いやがって
You whine too much.
（ホームレスの男）
おわっ うう…
（デーモン３）
もう少し生きのいいのは
なかったのかよ！
You couldn't find a fresher one?
We'll be done with this in a second.
こんなんじゃ すぐ終わっちまう
（デーモン１）拾えよ
俺たちも張り合いないからな
Pick it up.
It'll make it more interesting.
（デーモン１）ナイフと拳銃だ
（ホームレスの男）くう…はあはあ
It's a knife and a gun.
ははっ はっ はっ
はあ はあ
&lrm;（激しい音楽）
&lrm;があっ くっ
&lrm;ひいいいっ うあああ
（銃声）
（長崎）はあ…
Where are you?
（ホームレスの男）どこだ！
撃つぞ！ あ は…
ああっ
（了）見えるか？
Can you see?
おう 何不自由なくな
-Yeah, clear as day.
-Hurry.
急げ
（明）おう
（デーモン１）ん？
（長崎）ひっ！ しまった
こっちに来る ん…
Shit! It's coming this way.
（デーモン１）何かいる
Something's there.
You!
（明）お前ら！
Did you guys do it?
The chief priest at Hosen Temple, too?
お前らがやったのか
宝仙寺の住職さんも
はあ はあ…
（デーモン２）お仲間か
-You're one of us.
-You're late.
（デーモン３）遅かったな
だいたい食っちまった
We ate most of it.
何だお前 泣いてんのか？
What? Are you crying?
（亜樹子）突然泣きだしちゃって
She started crying suddenly...
（明）お前らが食った
You guys ate him.
（長崎）んん…
You guys killed them!
お前らが殺したあー
ガァ～ッ
（デーモン２）アモン！
Amon.
俺たち同じ悪魔だぞ！
We're all the same devils.
（デビルマン）
俺は悪魔ではない！ 俺は―
I'm not a devil.
I'm...
デビルマンだ！
Devilman!
（デーモン１）グッ うおっ
ぎゃあ
（デーモン３）お！ おい
Hey!
（了）赤外線
（長崎）ぐひっ
Infrared light?
カメラ！
A camera.
おい 待て！ クソッ！
Hey, wait. Damn it!
（デーモン３の叫び声）
（うなり声）
明！ 明！ 明！
Akira. Akira.
Akira, you were seen.
Someone other than me was filming you.
見られた！ 俺以外のヤツが
お前を撮っていた！
多分 お前が
デビル化するところも！
They got when when you changed
into a devil, too!
This is a huge scoop.
大変な大スクープだ
これは歴史だって変えちまう
This could change history.
俺は…
俺はそういう画(え)を撮ったんだ！
I filmed something that can do that.
&lrm;
Subtitles by
Daniel Marchildon